Guide to the Charles S. Tidball papers, 1949-1999 MS0207.UA
Special Collections Research Center, The George Washington University
Charles S. Tidball papers
1949-1999
Special Collections Research Center, The George Washington University
Tidball, Charles S.
MS0207.UA
2 Linear Feet
Collection includes computer programming materials developed at GW between 1966 and 1980. It also contains Educational Computing Technology Workshop materials, TMIS Training Program Modules, Medical Computer Programming for Patients and other items such as a Chi-Square, Data Red, Deeds, MLS, Paired T-Test, Plot 12A, Rankcorr, Dersim Notebook, Orcon/S2632, POMR, Pharmacokinetics, Drug-Receptor Interactions and Regresso, Serdis, T-Test, Variance.
Restrictions on Access
Some records may be restricted.
Acquisition Information
Dr. Tidball, along with M. Elizabeth Tidball (Professor Emeritus of Physiology at The George Washington University) donated the collection to Special Collections in 1993.
Biographical Note
Charles S. Tidball is Professor Emeritus of Computer Medicine and of Neurological Surgery at The George Washington University. In addition to his many accomplishments as a physician and as a scholar in the field of physiology, he also has made significant contributions to the field of education as a computer scientist. He founded an Educational Computing Technology Program for the Department of Education at The George Washington University. Dr. Tidball was honored by George Washington University with its President's Medal, the highest honor the university can bestow. This note was written in 2005.
Collection Scope and Content
Materials in this collection include computer programming materials developed at GW between 1966 and 1980. It also contains Educational Computing Technology Workshop materials, TMIS Training Program Modules, Medical Computer Programming for Patients and other items such as a Chi-Square, Data Red, Deeds, MLS, Paired T-Test, Plot 12A, Rankcorr, Dersim Notebook, Orcon/S2632, POMR, Pharmacokinetics, Drug-Receptor Interactions and Regresso, Serdis, T-Test, Variance.
Collection Organization
Organized in two series.
bib #
3045859
Physiology; Computers; Computer programming; Washington (D.C.); George Washington University. School of Education and Human Development; George Washington University; University of Chicago; Washington Academy of Sciences (Washington, D.C.); Tidball, Charles S.
- Personal papers, 1949-1999; MS0207 Series 1; 2 Linear feet (Box 2, Box 1)
  Scope and Contents note
  Materials in this collection include computer programming materials developed at GW between 1966 and 1980. It also contains Educational Computing Technology Workshop materials, TMIS Training Program Modules, Medical Computer Programming for Patients and other items such as a Chi-Square, Data Red, Deeds, MLS, Paired T-Test, Plot 12A, Rankcorr, Dersim Notebook, Orcon/S2632, POMR, Pharmacokinetics, Drug-Receptor Interactions and Regresso, Serdis, T-Test, Variance.
  - Hood College --- Convocation, 1999 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Delta Sigma Rha --- Membership Certificate, 1949 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - American Chemical Society --- Bachelor Degree Certificate, 1950 (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - The Graduate School Of Arts And Sciences of The George Washington University announces the final examination of Patricia Wakefield for the degree of Ph.D, 1972 (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - The Graduate Council of The George Washington University announces the final examination of Andrew Michael Goldner for the degree of Ph.D, 1966 (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - GW Medicine Anniversary Issue --- Decade of Accomplishment, undated (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - Wesleyan University --- Commencement, 06/11/1950 (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - The Tidball Learning Library, undated (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - The ST. Albans News, 10/26/1968 (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - Dr. Tidball Awarded Grant For Science Study, 05/1966 (Box 1, Folder 10)
  - Washington Academy of Sciences --- Annual Awards Dinner Meeting, 01/25/1968 (Box 1, Folder 11)
  - Bulletin of the Alumni Association, School of Medicine, University of Chicago, 1958 (Box 1, Folder 12)
  - The George Washington University --- One Hundred and Forty-fifth Year Winter Convocation and the Inauguration of Lloyd Hartman Elliott, Fourteenth President of the University, 1966 (Box 1, Folder 13)
  - The George Washington University Inauguration of Thomas Henry Carroll as the Thirteenth President, 1961 (Box 1, Folder 14)
  - The One Hundred & Twenty-Fourth Annual Commencement, Wilson College 1869-1994, 05/22/1994 (Box 1, Folder 15)
  - The University of Chicago --- Two Hundred Seventy-Seventh Convocation, 03/21/1958 (Box 1, Folder 16)
  - MiniMEDLINE Tutorial, undated (Box 1, Folder 17)
  - BASICLRN, undated (Box 1, Folder 18)
  - Computer Literacy, undated (Box 1, Folder 19)
  - The BASIC Handbook --- Encyclopedia of the BASIC Computer Language, by David A. Lien, 1981 (Box 2, Folder 1)
  - Basic And The Personal Computer, by Thomas Dwyer & Margot Critchfield, 1982 (Box 2, Folder 2)
  - Introduction to BASIC, 1982 (Box 2, Folder 3)
  - BASIC by Microsoft Corp., undated (Box 2, Folder 4)
- Personal papers, undated; MS0207 Series 2; 2 Linear feet (Box 1, Box 4, Box 3, Box 2)
  - Chi-Square, Data Red, Deed, MLS, Paired T-Test, Plot 12A, Rankcorr, undated (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Dersim Notebook, undated (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Orcon/S2632, undated (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Orcon/S2632, undated (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - POMR, undated (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - POMR, undated (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - Pharmacokinetics, undated (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - Drug-Receptor Interactions, undated (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - Regresso, Serdis, T-Test, Variance, undated (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - PILOT, undated (Box 1, Folder 10)
  - PILOT, undated (Box 1, Folder 11)
  - FOCAL - 12 Programming Manual, undated (Box 1, Folder 12)
  - FOCAL - 12 Listing, undated (Box 1, Folder 13)
  - FOCAL 8 Manuals, undated (Box 1, Folder 14)
  - 8K Basic, undated (Box 1, Folder 15)
  - CBASIC User's Guide, undated (Box 1, Folder 16)
  - Omsi - Software Dev. Group Intro & Com.sum, undated (Box 1, Folder 17)
  - Omsi Basic, undated (Box 1, Folder 18)
  - OSU General Intro, Using the OSU System, Monitors Guide, Trial User Courses, undated (Box 1, Folder 19)
  - OSU - ACIBA, undated (Box 1, Folder 20)
  - OSU - SERAB, undated (Box 1, Folder 21)
  - Informational Retrieval, undated (Box 1, Folder 22)
  - Informational Retrieval, undated (Box 1, Folder 23)
  - FOCAL, undated (Box 1, Folder 24)
  - BASIC, undated (Box 1, Folder 25)
  - MIS Video, 06/13/1978 (Box 2, Folder 1)
  - TidBall Collection, undated (Box 2, Folder 2)
  - HumRRD, undated (Box 2, Folder 3)
  - National Health Education Network, undated (Box 2, Folder 4)
  - National Health Education Network, undated (Box 2, Folder 5)
  - National Health Education Network, undated (Box 2, Folder 6)
  - USAGE, undated (Box 2, Folder 7)
  - Cornell University Medical Collection, undated (Box 2, Folder 8)
  - Correspondence, undated (Box 2, Folder 9)
  - Current Bylaws and Article of Incorporation, undated (Box 2, Folder 10)
  - HEN Receipts, undated (Box 2, Folder 11)
  - Progress Report A, undated (Box 2, Folder 12)
  - Progress Report B, undated (Box 2, Folder 13)
  - Tax Exempt Application, undated (Box 2, Folder 14)
  - Williams, Myers, and Quiggle, undated (Box 2, Folder 15)
  - Minutes, undated (Box 2, Folder 16)
  - G. David Anderson Archives Gelman, undated (Box 3, Folder 1)
  - Patient 1 Medical Computer Programming, undated (Box 3, Folder 2)
  - Patient 2 Medical Computer Programming, undated (Box 3, Folder 3)
  - Patient 3 Medical Computer Programming, undated (Box 3, Folder 4)
  - Patient 4 Medical Computer Programming, undated (Box 3, Folder 5)
  - Patient 5 Medical Computer Programming, undated (Box 3, Folder 6)
  - Patient 6 Medical Computer Programming, undated (Box 3, Folder 7)
  - Patient 7 Medical Computer Programming, undated (Box 3, Folder 8)
  - Patient 8 Medical Computer Programming, undated (Box 3, Folder 9)
  - Patient 9 Medical Computer Programming, undated (Box 3, Folder 10)
  - FDA Scientific Associates Training Program, undated (Box 3, Folder 11)
  - Patient 1 Medical Computer Programming II, undated (Box 3, Folder 12)
  - Patient 2 Medical Computer Programming II, undated (Box 3, Folder 13)
  - Patient 3 Medical Computer Programming II, undated (Box 3, Folder 14)
  - Patient 4 Medical Computer Programming II, undated (Box 3, Folder 15)
  - Patient 5 Medical Computer Programming II, undated (Box 3, Folder 16)
  - Patient 6 Medical Computer Programming II, undated (Box 3, Folder 17)
  - Patient 7 Medical Computer Programming II, undated (Box 3, Folder 18)
  - Patient 8 Medical Computer Programming II, undated (Box 3, Folder 19)
  - Patient 9 Medical Computer Programming II, undated (Box 3, Folder 20)
  - Patient 10 Medical Computer Programming II, undated (Box 3, Folder 21)
  - Patient 11 Medical Computer Programming II, undated (Box 3, Folder 22)
  - Patient 12 Medical Computer Programming II, undated (Box 3, Folder 23)
  - Patient 13 Medical Computer Programming II, undated (Box 3, Folder 24)
  - Patient 14 Medical Computer Programming II, undated (Box 3, Folder 25)
  - Educational Computing Technology 1, undated (Box 3, Folder 26)
  - Educational Computing Technology 2, undated (Box 3, Folder 27)
  - Educational Computing Technology 3, undated (Box 3, Folder 28)
  - Educational Computing Technology 4, undated (Box 3, Folder 29)
  - Educational Computing Technology 5, undated (Box 3, Folder 30)
  - Educational Computing Technology 6, undated (Box 3, Folder 31)
  - Educational Computing Technology 7, undated (Box 3, Folder 32)
  - Workshop I, 1966 (Box 3, Folder 33)
  - Workshop II, 1966 (Box 3, Folder 34)
  - Workshop III, 1966 (Box 3, Folder 35)
  - Workshop IV, 1966 (Box 3, Folder 36)
  - Workshop V, 1966 (Box 3, Folder 37)
  - Workshop VI, 1966 (Box 3, Folder 38)
  - Workshop VII, 1966 (Box 3, Folder 39)
  - Workshop VIII, 1966 (Box 3, Folder 40)
  - Workshop IX, 1966 (Box 3, Folder 41)
  - Elementary Medical Statistics, 1966 (Box 3, Folder 42)
  - Workshop I, 1967 (Box 3, Folder 43)
  - Workshop I, 1967 (Box 3, Folder 44)
  - Workshop I, 1967 (Box 3, Folder 45)
  - Workshop I, 1967 (Box 3, Folder 46)
  - Workshop II, 1967 (Box 3, Folder 47)
  - Workshop III, 1967 (Box 3, Folder 48)
  - Workshop IV, 1967 (Box 3, Folder 49)
  - Workshop V, 1967 (Box 3, Folder 50)
  - Workshop VI, 1967 (Box 3, Folder 51)
  - Workshop VII, 1967 (Box 3, Folder 52)
  - Workshop VIII, 1967 (Box 3, Folder 53)
  - Workshop IX, 1967 (Box 3, Folder 54)
  - TMIS Training Program Module 1-3, undated (Box 4, Folder 1)
  - TMIS Training Program Module 4, undated (Box 4, Folder 2)
  - TMIS Training Program Module 5, undated (Box 4, Folder 3)
  - TMIS Training Program Module 6, undated (Box 4, Folder 4)
  - Digital Equipt. Corporation: PDP - 12 System Reference Manual, 1971-1972 (Box 4, Folder 5)
  - Digital Equipt. Corporation: PDP - 12 System Reference Manual, 1971-1972 (Box 4, Folder 6)
  - Digital Equipt. Corporation: PDP - 8 ETOS Time Shared Operation System Acid-Base Chemistry, 1974-1975 (Box 4, Folder 7)
  - Digital Equipt. Corporation: PDP - 8 ETOS Time Shared Operation System Acid-Base Chemistry, 1974-1975 (Box 4, Folder 8)
  - Digital Equipt. Corporation: PDP - 8 Implementation of PILOT Part 1 Technical, 1975-1976 (Box 4, Folder 9)
  - Digital Equipt. Corporation: PDP - 8 Implementation of PILOT Part 1 Business, 1975-1976 (Box 4, Folder 10)
  - SWTP S/09 1980-1981 UNIFEX TLLBasic, undated (Box 4, Folder 11)
  - SWTP S/09 1980-1981 UNIFEX TLLBasic, undated (Box 4, Folder 12)
  - Digital Equipt. Corporation: PDP - 12 Time Sharing System, 1971-1972 (Box 4, Folder 13)
  - Digital Equipt. Corporation: PDP - 8 Time Sharing System, 1971-1972 (Box 4, Folder 14)
  - IBM Mainframe Acid Base Chemistry APL, 1969-1970 (Box 4, Folder 15)
  - IBM Mainframe Acid Base Chemistry APL, 1969-1970 (Box 4, Folder 16)
  - Digital Equipt. Corporation: PDP - 8 STARLN, 1973-1974 (Box 4, Folder 17)
  - Digital Equipt. Corporation: STARLN, 1973-1974 (Box 4, Folder 18)
  - Digital Equipt. Corporation: PDP - 8 FOCLEARN, 1974-1975 (Box 4, Folder 19)
  - Digital Equipt. Corporation: PDP - 8 FOCLEARN, 1974-1975 (Box 4, Folder 20)
  - Digital Equipt. Corporation: PDP - 8 CALILEARN, 1973-1974 (Box 4, Folder 21)
  - Digital Equipt. Corporation: PDP - 8 LIBLEARN, 1973-1974 (Box 4, Folder 22)
  - Digital Equipt. Corporation: PDP - 8 TERMLEARN, 1973-1974 (Box 4, Folder 23)